#### Contato

+351 926 479 947 (Mobile) marcelocruz21@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mmcruz (LinkedIn)

# Principais competências

Sales Management
IT Service Management
Business Strategy

### Languages

Inglês (Full Professional)
Espanhol (Professional Working)
Português (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards Visão 21

# Marcelo Cruz

Ajudando empresas a se tornarem mais competitivas. Lisbon Area, Portugal

### Resumo

Senior Professional with over 27 years of experience with information technology, including management systems and services, project management and business processes and sales management. Overcoming consistent results, assisting in the optimization of costs, rationalization of resources, improved quality of care, risk reduction and alignment with business operating results.

Highlighting the following activities:

Management of sales strategies in the business environment; Construction and sales pipeline management for the portfolio of collaboration software and productivity, working with account managers and members of the sales team.

Quality of management implementations in the post sale strengthening the relationship and protecting the customer base; Building and maintaining a solid customer base reference and case studies for accelerating sales cycles and increase the perception of brand presence in the market.

# Experiência

ARTSOFT Business Software Partner Account Manager janeiro de 2020 - Present (3 meses) Lisboa e Região, Portugal

#### Stefanini

Senior Business Manager novembro de 2018 - novembro de 2019 (1 ano 1 mês) Rio de Janeiro

#### **TOTVS**

Senior Account Executive outubro de 2015 - outubro de 2018 (3 anos 1 mês)

Rio de Janeiro Area, Brazil

#### Oracle

Senior Account Executive abril de 2014 - maio de 2015 (1 ano 2 meses)

Rio de Janeiro

#### IBM

#### Account Executive

junho de 2009 - março de 2014 (4 anos 10 meses)

Rio de Janeiro

#### **Embratel**

9 anos 10 meses

#### IT Manager

janeiro de 2007 - junho de 2009 (2 anos 6 meses)

Rio de Janeiro

## IT Project and Process Manager

setembro de 2002 - dezembro de 2006 (4 anos 4 meses)

Rio de Janeiro

#### **Network Analyst**

setembro de 1999 - agosto de 2002 (3 anos)

Rio de Janeiro

# Cesar Sucupira Educação e Consultoria

**IT Coordinator** 

novembro de 1997 - agosto de 1999 (1 ano 10 meses)

Rio de Janeiro

#### Nitnet

**Support Coordinator** 

janeiro de 1996 - outubro de 1997 (1 ano 10 meses)

Rio de Janeiro

#### Metha

System Analyst

1993 - 1995 (2 anos)

Rio de Janeiro

# Formação acadêmica

### Ibmec

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Finance and Capital Market  $\cdot$  (2019 - 2020)

Universidade Federal Fluminense Graduate, Computer Science · (1990 - 1997)

Colegio Souza Marques 20 Grau, 20 Grau · (1987 - 1988)